Welcome back to the Go Go Golems lab spider welcome back to the welcome back to the Go Go Golems lab today a special episode
we're gonna be rabbit holeing with LLMs I'm sure you've gone down deep the rabbit hole talking about one thing or the other
I'll show you what my workflow looks and how I use it to basically learn new things, learn new skills both in terms of how
LLMs work, what you can do with LLMs, what can tools do that are out there, but also just pure fundamental knowledge that
will help me create better software at the end of the day, right?
So let's imagine that I wanna do something random I have a certain task I'm gonna go to Chat GPT and I'm gonna use that as
a starting point for a rabbit hole.
So So my my today's today's rabbit rabbit hole.
hole it's a pretty stupid one.
It's I want to do the square root of something so square root of and I'm gonna see you know I'm I'm using this to show how
LLMs can be wrong as well I'm gonna be nah I'm not sure I really trust this cause it's an LLM I don't really see what I have
I wanna learn more about how to get computers to do square roots because I do want to have you know a correct result so I'm
an instant I did that on purpose I would usually never use instant I would go to thinking at least put standard thinking so
that would be the first thing is hey instant did this I don't really trust that it was really fast but I'm not really sure
so what I'm gonna do now is I'm gonna see what does light thinking say you know so first step of the rabbit hole is basically
Is basically iterating on what the LLM does and I don't know if I can go back to the previous we can kind of start checking
so it's kind of the same is it true no one knows because there are LLMs right So here same thing and now I'm gonna go to standard
thinking why not learn a little bit about what these different thinking levels do oh we can see here we have a little bit
more happening and it is writing some code so now suddenly we can have a little bit more information we can see oh well this
code Python tells us the integer is this it does double check the integer which is amazing I actually hadn't seen that before
this is pretty cool It's a cool pattern discovered something learned something right it's bracketing square roots interesting
thing might go into my knowledge base which we'll get to later And and I now see how to do it in Python.
I can go back and see does this fully match what we had?
No, you can start to see the real value as computed by Python is this compared to the light thinking it's this and then compared
to the the original one this is interesting this one is actually correct this was the first one we did with instant so interesting
interesting here however we do have the code which means that we can take this code and we can you know we can we can basically
run it on our own anyway we're not done yet we're gonna go to extended thinking and see what happens there because we're rabbit
holeing so I do these things fairly often where I'm I feel bored I'm gonna do something here what's interesting is Is we we
don't see the Python code so maybe it got censored away and it did actually run the Python code, which is what I suspect happened
here I suspect it actually ran the code it's just not showing that to us and here we we do have this up to the decimal right
yeah so I suspect this one render code it doesn't show it to us it's interesting to see let's go to heavy thinking and I'm
not sure if you know if the thinking level here does make that much of a difference it's hard to tell with these censored
models right no need for the web so here it's definitely thinking longer what's interesting is that it was Streaming streaming
this this, but but here here it it puts puts it it into a single one and I can use a calculator and then here we can tell
it's okay, so we learned a little bit of something since we have you know a lot of time to spend I'm gonna open Pi gonna go
into my little Patreon and I'm gonna go into the videos and then I'm gonna go into my square root and we're gonna try out
the different models here so I'm using Kimmy K two P five turbo and I'm literally gonna put in the same prompt cause I wanna
see within the context of a coding agent what does it do the small model actually runs Python right and I actually don't know
how to regenerate but interesting thing it ran Python I have the Python code pretty good if I run it again what happens here
Here it's it's doing the doing the same Python roughly it's doing two Pythons interesting, right?
So here it's doing a decimal something new that I learned right I didn't know that this existed if we go back to I think it
was number two number three so interestingly by the way light thinking was wrong instant was right so I the bracketing here
so I'm gonna try that bracket E square root right so here we can see the prompting of Kimi K two P five is something I have
to learn cause if I had use another model I would have I if I had used maybe even GPT five it It would have would worked have
worked the way the way intended intended.
is no compute the bracketed E square root to validate I hope that this works right so now we have a nice little piece of code
that we could potentially reuse, right?
I this little bracketing kind of thing so I can tell oh Kim Ep two I learned something about prompting Kimi for example I
got some Python and then maybe I can say make a little interactive web app in Python so now I can leverage the fact that I'm
in a coding agent that I have a really fast model that it has already written code that I find interesting to say hey why
not make it interactive because having interactive little applications are fun and fun is Fun what is makes you what makes
learn you learn often often.
it's It's playing with things helps you learn, and now I can see right it started it it's gonna navigate to it.
It kind of looks very LLM esque.
It decided to take a screenshot sure why not?
It decided to click on it.
that's also very interesting have to.
I know that the playwright MCP was turned on so maybe it indexed pretty strongly on it, and now we can see we have a nice
little application to play with square roots, right?
It's taking screenshots.
Sure I don't know how much of its context window it's wasting here but it is definitely interesting, right now I have a little
application to bracket things and it's make a slider for the now I don't I don't want to have a slider.
perfect.
perfect so So we've gone through the process of starting with I want to compute the square root to trying four different settings
in Chat GPT and trying to understand what they did or what they didn't do to testing out Kimmy, learning a little bit about
Kimi prompting and now having a little square root app that's interactive that I can reuse in the future maybe have a daughter
and I want to show her some math problems maybe I just having fun but now we can go one step further right we saw LLMs not
good at math writing code pretty good at if they can write code they can write interactive code pretty fun we saw that Kimmy
has certain behaviors when prompting I I literally got it this morning so it's very new to me the next thing we can do is
hey I want to learn about square root and computation I don't know how a computer does square root right so I can literally
say how does a computer do square root and And I'm gonna do this, but also sticking with the you know with the overall context
concept I'm going to go back to standard maybe and then just say this here we have the full thinking stream which often is
hidden right often we'll just see this I love looking at them and that's why I think small models are really powerful is that
this might explain why it does some nonsense later on and here I don't see why it doesn't I don't I don't understand why it
did nonsense right if we go back here and light thinking wrong I don't know why did it call a tool did it not why is this
wrong and why is this correct?
I don't know here I see I have a fairly good chance of understanding if it did X Y Z or not and I think as Models models get
get more more and and more more powerful powerful.
It's it's actually actually more more interesting to understand why a model didn't do the right thing than having models that
incrementally do a you know ninety nine percent the right thing and then ninety nine percent dot five the right thing I don't
think that's all that interesting when we can actually just start having a good understanding of what these things do so what's
interesting here is it will always it will often surface adjacent stuff that it doesn't reuse in the future but that is actually
fairly interesting to go look up on our own right so here we can start doing the kind of recursive rabbit holeing which is
you know we got some information here cool I found some youth method met met met met met met met met met method but I can
start experimenting even further which is hey what if I just paste the stuff from Kimmy in here and you can see my prompting
is very as we saw in the first video that I'm I'm gonna link gonna somewhere link somewhere in here in here I I the first
time I do this so I think of it in terms of LLMs are good at dealing with messy content in ways that human can't right so
I don't really need to put care into certain words or so or I well well we'll get back to putting care in certain words but
I can put really messy stuff in there and see what happens is is my point so what I'm interested in I'm curious if it will
index on these words is these two is Goldschmidt I don't know about we saw that the Newton algorithm was something that I
brought up before we have the fast inverse square root from Quake which if you don't know about is very interesting the chordic
algorithms are really interesting too so in this little tiny little snippet of thinking we do get a really wide spray probabilistic
while however the non thinking output is But often is tailored often to tailored have to have a certain a certain output output
format at certain rigor style so often less interesting for surfacing random new information for rabbit holeing.
So really, really enjoy having this in small models and then now our output out of Chat GPT which has search I don't know
I don't think it's searched here we'll get back to that now I have some pretty good information I'm gonna skip over this but
if I were really rabbit holeing I would read this carefully and maybe that would be you know my little occ occ occ occ occ
occ occ occ occ occ occ occupation for for the evening however what we can do to go even further and go back to this idea
of playing is going back to a very expansive model that tries a lot of things and makes things really nice and stuff that
so we're gonna go Gonna to go to Claude Claude and and we're we're gonna gonna go to Claude.
We're gonna paste this in again very rough and we're gonna say research and then make a nice detail interactive article in
the style of Brett Victor essays who has written a lot about what is learning, what does computation allow us to do in terms
of learning and leverage the fact that we have code writing for free to build playgrounds that really will help us learn something
you can read text, you can try to remember it, but it doesn't really stick with you interacting with something has much higher
chance of sticking with you.
That's why when you learn you often do labs exercises, internships is usually where the knowledge sticks versus textbook learning,
which can be pretty forgettable.
so there we go.
I would start just rabbit holing by putting all of these things Things in here in here and I know and I know it it will will
reset. research each of these little words in here and kind of put them into an interactive context.
I don't really care about what this is going to be because I'm rabbit holing but now I'm starting to have real links.
That's why I said research and now detailed also because I want it to be a a real article not just a random React app I want
to be able to click on these links.
That's why I said interactive article and then Brig Victor is you know a stylistic word that will surface a certain type of
not just output format but also methodology and Bret Victor's work is think is pretty much about playing about rabbit holeing
about using this kind of playful learning so while this is going we can go back to here To here to to Chat GPT who is a little
bit more rigorous and uptight and start thinking about actual tools we could use to leverage the things that we've been playing
with right So because I don't really know much about Taylor series for example and I'm going to speed this up for the sake
of finishing the video I was gonna say what are concretely useful applications of Taylor series that I could put into a small
program tool because besides using this for learning and making little toy prototypes or toys or games you know interactive
games maybe there's some real useful tools that I can get out of it that I don't even know about but that might be useful
for my daily work right so sure little scientific calculator Later this is this is where where it gets it gets interesting
if you're into embedded software.
This might start to be really interesting.
So we're gonna pretend we have a little calculator that we can program and see, right and we're gonna build this or maybe
an approximation error explorer that's also a good good good idea so we're gonna do two things at once we're going to tailor
approximation workbench so make an interactive canvas tool to visualize error in Taylor series for example right and interactive
canvas I think is going to summon the Chat GPT artifacts it's it's a little bit hard to coax it out versus Claude where it's
a little bit hard to to make it not appear so learning some prompting here as well and here and here create creating an HTML
file that's exactly what I wanted.
So here we're building something that is less about having fun and discovery and more about I want a useful tool for this
right and in the meantime we're going to see for example is Kinney capable of writing a C calculator write a C scientific
calculator with these four operations then I'm just gonna paste whatever I had from over here and then build it right I I
guess I didn't even have to do this so does Kimmy work well with these kinds of prompt how long does it think is this going
to work is it going to have trouble even compiling it what is it going to do here very interesting questions but also at the
end of the day I will have a C calculator to do it right Which I which can I can then then put onto put onto my my embedded
device and do sign without having to install a library.
This could be very useful, so little bug interesting we might wanna, you know, compare it to other models which which might
be fun so we'll try that and then in the meantime we do have our interactive Brett Victor article here right so we can start
playing with these and kind of see these different little things so I've seen it yeah it does change those I've seen it do
this thing where the slider is at the top and then you have to scroll down to view the To view to the view to the view graph
the graph so that might be something to to prompt to to add to the prompt to say you know make sure that the interactive part
is fits within one screen but here pretty interesting article it covers the quake trick it doesn't have any links so that
might also be something to add into a prompt engineering right and that tells us the next time we do interactive articles
we might do them here we might just be this is great CSS maybe a smaller model or maybe Chat GPT is not great at CSS but what
we're going to do referring back to the previous video we want useful tokens here we have useful CSS tokens we have useful
you know a scaffold for interactive things but maybe GPT is better at filling out the the the interactive things right So
next idea is Interactive interactive prototype prototype and here we're building tools still trying to build this tool.
What we're going to do in the meantime is we're going to branch this into new chat and now we're going to do some actual research,
right?
Research great resources about these topics very rabbit holy prompt I'm gonna put it to standard thinking just so that we
don't spend all day on this and in the meantime you know we've started gathering a lot of little things without spending a
lot of tokens but we are learning a lot even if we don't learn necessarily about signing cost cosign we will maybe learn about
hey how does Kimmy do all of this what issues does Kimmy have did it even do this all correctly was it able to test its own
thing this is great right these are interesting things but is Is it it correct?
correct? I don't know I don't know, but we but have we have tools tools to verify it, right?
Because we have cross verify against Python standard library implementations can Kimmy do this?
Can Kimmy do quick check tests?
How does it going to to build this all very interesting questions is is it going to generate random values?
No, it has a set of fixed values so maybe we can do some some some some some fuzz testing how is it going to oh I didn't know
that you could use symmetric symmetrical properties to test it there's all kinds of interesting things that surface from models
maybe it will fail with some syntax errors also useful information gain from the rabbit hole and so we'll see there's because
this is all code at this point even though the model is not a model that I trust at all because it's so small and fast the
code is The something code is something I I can can verify.
I can put back into a bigger model to maybe understand why it broke, and this will tell me a lot about Kimmy itself.
In the meantime, we start to have, you know, the real resources.
So if I do want to learn as a human, if you're into math, you can start looking at these things and doing some real math learning
and you can say you know give me some exercises you can turn on the little learning thing down here and explore how this works
right you can do quizzes I think is the learning thing all kinds of things that you can go starting from a simple little question
oh I didn't see that before see learning something new do we now have our little self contained self contained error visualizer
Visualizer I guess we have I guess we have it it's quite pretty so here again is do I trust the math necessarily?
Not necessarily, but I do, for example, have I don't even know what this is about just kind of seems broken I I'm not sure
what I'm looking at so you know that's also information where I'm is the model broken do I don't understand this?
What is this all about error plot function and Taylor polynomial test is the exact function so do I need to zoom in maybe
is that the zoom?
Yeah, okay so so I I understand a little bit better what's going on so if we do have higher degrees yeah we'll be able to
accommodate for a wider part Part and then I don't know if the samples do change anything so useful here again maybe this
is wrong but at least you know the plotting thing is pretty interesting so the plotting is something I might want to extract
it's cool because now I have HTML right so last thing but not least deep research and now I'm gonna say explain everything
about this last interactive widget and because I've deep research on it's going to suggest different it's gonna suggest one
ki kind of research right and then I'm going to say no I actually I care about the computational foundations and the math
so I don't care about the widget I don't care about the canvas rendering but maybe that's That's something something that
that you know you know would have what I've caught caught my my attention attention is for if I were rabbit holeing would
be yeah, I I the plot tell me more about that and so here this is what I personally am more interested in it's gonna research
and it's gonna give me a Pdf that I'm basically going to read I I to print those out and make them into my into my little
morning magazine so here we have quizzes I usually didn't find those all that useful but maybe you do I also find not very
useful in here I them in markdown we saw this and then we saw here our self improving kind of scaffold and we can go back
and reuse this code or we say this is all crap that's also a valuable knowledge to know where the limits of a small fast model
very important to know and And I I hope hope this this was a good insight into rabbit holing with LLMs, so have fun, play
with all of these things, learn some fundamentals that will always be useful because next time you have you want to do cosine
and sine you'll be I know it Taylor series, I know how to test it, I have some graphs, I have everything ready and all of
this output is something you should store into a knowledge base which is going to be the topic of a future video